<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Latest News on Metadot</title><link>https://metadot.com/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Latest News on Metadot</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 10:07:21 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://metadot.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Connecting the Continents: How We Operate a Global Team</title><link>https://metadot.com/blog/globalteam/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 10:07:21 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://metadot.com/blog/globalteam/</guid><description>The United States, Canada, France, and Germany - the Metadot team is spread all throughout the world. While we live in these countries, we represent many different cultures and diverse backgrounds - all connected through our organization, Metadot. Our diversity is something we celebrate, and we consider it to be one of our greatest strengths. Each member of our team brings a unique and different skill set, as well as perspectives and belief systems that help us tackle even the toughest challenges.</description></item><item><title>The Sitting Disease: How your Workweek Habits are Damaging your Health</title><link>https://metadot.com/blog/thesittingdisease/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 10:07:21 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://metadot.com/blog/thesittingdisease/</guid><description>“We are sitting ourselves to death.” A shocking, yet true statement from Dr. James Levine about the unintentional danger we put ourselves in each day just by living our lives. Our health classes teach us the risk of things like eating too much junk food, or the dangers of smoking - yet have us in a system where we often spend hours a day sitting down. When we graduate, we move onto a university where we spend more time sitting, or to a job where we most likely spend our days at a desk.</description></item><item><title>Zoom Fatigue: How to Beat the Burnout of Remote Work Meetings</title><link>https://metadot.com/blog/zoomfatigue/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 10:07:21 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://metadot.com/blog/zoomfatigue/</guid><description>Zoom calls are something everyone has become familiar with especially during the pandemic. Whether its a virtual birthday party, long-distance family game night or just the classic 9 am work meeting - Zoom has become a more consistent part of our daily lives. It has allowed companies to keep operating, families to stay connected, and the world to shift the way we once viewed work structures. Amidst all the positives, Zoom and other virtual communication platforms have their negatives.</description></item><item><title>Evolving Evaluations in the Workplace</title><link>https://metadot.com/blog/360reviews/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 10:07:21 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://metadot.com/blog/360reviews/</guid><description>Evaluation is an essential and crucial part of business. It drives change and areas of opportunity, and is what separates a company from being average to amazing. What is great about 360 Reviews is it gives the opportunity to go full-circle. Each person - no matter the position, is given the opportunity to give and receive feedback. Managers learn their leading style, and areas that they show their strengths. Employees learn about their working habits, and how to better maximize their potential.</description></item><item><title>The Buddy System: Remote Onboarding made Simple</title><link>https://metadot.com/blog/thebuddysystem/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 10:07:21 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://metadot.com/blog/thebuddysystem/</guid><description>As professionals, everyone can relate to the new job nerves and excitement that comes with the start of a new opportunity. There are so many colleagues to meet, procedures to learn, and paperwork to complete. In a physical environment, this process can be difficult enough. Accomplishing a successful onboarding in a remote environment, can take this challenge to the next level. In the summer of 2020, faced with the difficulties of the pandemic and a growing team, Metadot created the “Buddy System”.</description></item><item><title>Four Attributes that Drive Successful Companies &amp; Individuals</title><link>https://metadot.com/blog/fourattributes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 10:07:21 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://metadot.com/blog/fourattributes/</guid><description>Success is a major goal that each individual and organization strives to achieve. It has many different layers, and interpretations - from an individual level to company wide. Based on studies from the Empirical Software Engineer team, as well as the methodology behind Deep Work, there have been four identifiable attributes that embrace the well-rounded skill sets of effective workers.
Working in a Meticulous Manner The number one attribute of an effective individual is their ability to pay attention to detail.</description></item><item><title>Deep Work: Minutes of Focus for a Lifetime of Results</title><link>https://metadot.com/blog/deepwork/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 10:07:21 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://metadot.com/blog/deepwork/</guid><description>I have faced challenges in my ability to focus for long periods as long as I can remember. From studying for tests in academics, to writing blog posts in my professional career - it is rare an activity can keep my focus without fidgeting or side-thoughts taking control. Being born into a world immersed in electronic entertainment, followed with the birth of social media - attention spans are shortening, including mine.</description></item><item><title>How Virtual Coffee Dates Impacted our Organization</title><link>https://metadot.com/blog/coffeedates/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 10:07:21 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://metadot.com/blog/coffeedates/</guid><description>As we entered another lock-down cycle amidst the Covid-19 pandemic, we knew that this was going to create challenges for everyone. Remote work certainly has its positives, but we knew that the lack of social interaction, and the ability to draw the line between work and home life - would become increasingly more difficult. Burnout is a very real, and very prominent issue that we aim to avoid at all costs.</description></item><item><title>Dress Code: How Metadot Tackles the Traditional Workplace Attire</title><link>https://metadot.com/blog/dresscode/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 10:07:21 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://metadot.com/blog/dresscode/</guid><description>The pandemic has made many companies trade the norm of button-ups and blazers to lounge pants and t-shirts. This is not necessarily a negative, many people love the comfortability and flexibility that comes with remote work attire. However, after weeks of working from home with failure to establish a balance between work and play, this can become an issue. Where collocated environments excel is in their nature of developing a strict line between work life and home life.</description></item><item><title>Meetings: A Four Step Process to Alleviate the Stress of Remote Meetings</title><link>https://metadot.com/blog/meetings/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 10:07:21 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://metadot.com/blog/meetings/</guid><description>We have all been there. The work day meetings that seem to last hours, and content that leaves you more confused than when you started. It is common for employees to have these feelings towards meetings, and they uphold this reputation in a variety of workplaces. Based on a study from The Business Journals, employees reported that 63% of meetings were not useful, and could have been handled through an email.</description></item><item><title>R.E.M.O.T.E Leadership - How To Guide a Remote Team To Success</title><link>https://metadot.com/blog/remote-leadership/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 10:07:21 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://metadot.com/blog/remote-leadership/</guid><description>With the onset of the Covid-19 pandemic and the global shift to working remotely, many companies have struggled with the inorganic transition from a collocated work environment to independent homeoffices. At Metadot, we have established an acronym that takes into account the vital responsibilities of those in management during this transition: R.E.M.O.T.E. Leaders are often skeptical about the true potential of an entirely virtual environment. However, many organizations have successfully made the transition, ultimately morphing to a more productive, flexible and happier workplace.</description></item><item><title>Onboarding To Onboarded - How My First Week Went at a Remote Global Tech Company</title><link>https://metadot.com/blog/onboarding-to-onboarded/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 10:07:21 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://metadot.com/blog/onboarding-to-onboarded/</guid><description>Before the Covid-19 pandemic, I worked in a variety of workplaces. Some were hands-on with teams of 70 plus people, while others were small local businesses - but what each of them had in common was the traditional collocated work environment. This meant days in the office, working with team members and having information accessible within a few feet. When businesses began to switch to a remote environment, I became concerned with what working remote meant for me.</description></item></channel></rss>